<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Introduction on Showcase Template</title><link>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/</link><description>Recent content in Introduction on Showcase Template</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/p5/Corte-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/p5/Corte-2/</guid><description>p5 iframe shortcodes embed p5.js code within an iframe element. There are two p5 iframe shortcodes: p5-iframe and p5-global-iframe.
p5-iframe # {{&amp;lt; p5-iframe ver=&amp;#34;1.5.0&amp;#34; sketch=&amp;#34;/path/to/sketch.js&amp;#34; lib1=&amp;#34;https://cdntolib1/lib1.js&amp;#34; width=&amp;#34;800&amp;#34; height=&amp;#34;600&amp;#34; &amp;gt;}} All parameters are optional but sketch. Default values are shown in the above snippet but for libs*. Up to lib5 libs may be specified.
Color relativity # Look at this brief explanation about what color relativity is.
p5-iframe markdown {{&amp;lt; p5-iframe sketch=&amp;#34;/visualcomp/sketches/colors.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/p5/Corte-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/p5/Corte-1/</guid><description>p5 div shortcodes embed p5.js code within a div element. There are two p5 div shortcodes: p5-div and p5-instance-div.
p5-div # {{&amp;lt; p5-div ver=&amp;#34;1.5.0&amp;#34; sketch=&amp;#34;/path/to/sketch.js&amp;#34; lib1=&amp;#34;https://cdntolib1/lib1.js&amp;#34; &amp;gt;}} All parameters are optional but sketch. Default values are shown in the above snippet but for libs*. Up to lib5 libs may be specified.
Scintillating grid # Look at this and also this among many more references there are.
p5-div markdown {{&amp;lt; p5-div sketch=&amp;#34;/showcase/sketches/scintillating.</description></item><item><title>Creating a New Theme</title><link>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/posts/creating-a-new-theme/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/posts/creating-a-new-theme/</guid><description>Introduction # This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover using CSS to style your theme.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start with creating a new site with a very basic template.</description></item><item><title>Migrate to Hugo from Jekyll</title><link>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/posts/migrate-from-jekyll/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/posts/migrate-from-jekyll/</guid><description>Move static content to static # Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with _ will be copied as-is to the _site output. Hugo keeps all static content under static. You should therefore move it all there. With Jekyll, something that looked like
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ images/ logo.png should become
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ static/ ▾ images/ logo.png Additionally, you&amp;rsquo;ll want any files that should reside at the root (such as CNAME) to be moved to static.</description></item><item><title>(Hu)go Template Primer</title><link>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/posts/goisforlovers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/posts/goisforlovers/</guid><description>Hugo uses the excellent Go html/template library for its template engine. It is an extremely lightweight engine that provides a very small amount of logic. In our experience that it is just the right amount of logic to be able to create a good static website. If you have used other template systems from different languages or frameworks you will find a lot of similarities in Go templates.
This document is a brief primer on using Go templates.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started with Hugo</title><link>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/posts/hugoisforlovers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/posts/hugoisforlovers/</guid><description>Step 1. Install Hugo # Go to Hugo releases and download the appropriate version for your OS and architecture.
Save it somewhere specific as we will be using it in the next step.
More complete instructions are available at Install Hugo
Step 2. Build the Docs # Hugo has its own example site which happens to also be the documentation site you are reading right now.
Follow the following steps:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/Corte1/ej1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/Corte1/ej1/</guid><description> Ejercicio 1 # Study, implement and discuss possible applications of some known visual phenomena and optical illusions.
Optical Ilussions # Simple # Complex #</description></item><item><title/><link>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/Corte1/ej2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/Corte1/ej2/</guid><description> Ejercicio 2 # Implement a color mapping application that helps people who are color blind see the colors around them.
Mapping Application #</description></item><item><title/><link>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/Corte1/ej3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/Corte1/ej3/</guid><description>Ejercicio 3 # Implement a pixelator video application and perform a benchmark of the results (color avg vs spatial coherence). How would you assess the visual quality of the results?
Spatial Coherence # En este ejemplo, implementamos una aplicación de pixelator para video, usando la captura de la videocamara. Para pixelar se usaron las dos diferentes formas o técnicas que se planteaban (promedio de color y coherencia espacial).
Color AVG # Cada color pixelado se calcula con el promedio de los colores en el grupo de la imagen original.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/Corte1/ej4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/Corte1/ej4/</guid><description>Ejercicio 4 # Develop a terrain visualization application. Check out the 3D terrain generation with Perlin noise coding train tutorial.
Introducción Y Transfondo # Antecedentes # Trabajo previo # Conclusiones y trabajos futuros # Mach bands # En el ejercicio que vamos a utilizar usamos la ilusion de contraste para la percepcion de la profundidad.
Terrain with Perlin noise # Siguiendo el tutorial, creamos una malla de triangulos, y darle diversas alturas usando el Perlin noise, el cual es una lista aleatoria de numeros manteniendo una relacion entre los numeros cercanos, lo que hace que el terreno parezca realista y al mismo tiempo sea parcialmente infinito.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/Corte1/ej5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/Corte1/ej5/</guid><description>Ejercicio 5 # Implement a kinegram and some moiré patterns which are close related visual phenomena to masking.
Visual masking # Un Kinegram es un fenomeno visual, donde utilizando una banda de mascara, al moverla sobre una imagen fija de fondo se crea una animacion de movimiento o diferencia entre ambos frames.
En el ejercicio que implementamos tenemos 4 ejemplos de como funcionan estas mascaras.
Mascara movimiento # En la esquina superior derecha tenemos 2 mascaras de diversos tamaños y direcciones cruzando entre si, lo que genera un patron que se repite.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/Corte1/ej6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/Corte1/ej6/</guid><description>Ejercicio 6 # Implement an animation with keyframes.
Temporal Coherence # Temporal coherence is the visual phenomenon present all across nature whereby the perceived color of a given point within a region of interest tend to vary more according to the elapsed time passed between two given moments. KeyFrames
Los KeyFrames, o frames clave son puntos en la animacion que marcan el inicio y el final de una transicion, siendo la transicion que vera el espectador la variacion de un key frame a otro, llenando de pormedio la transicion con frames conocidos como &amp;ldquo;inbetweens&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/Corte2/ej1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/Corte2/ej1/</guid><description> Ejercicio 1 Corte 2 #</description></item><item><title/><link>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/Corte3/ej1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/Corte3/ej1/</guid><description> Ejercicio 1 corte 3 #</description></item><item><title/><link>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/p5/Corte-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/p5/Corte-3/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Fabian Montes</title><link>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/Members/FabianMontes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/Members/FabianMontes/</guid><description>Fabián Andrés Montes Tobar # Quien Soy # Soy Fabián, Estudiante de Ingenieria de Sistemas.
Teniendo un fino interes en la manera que se puede percibir el mundo, resulta de lo mas interesante aprender como se puede transmitir por una pantalla todas esas percepciones que se sienten en el mundo real, poder transimitir con una imagen un sin fin de informacion de manera visual e interactiva.
Me fascina leer historias de fantasia, ver series, y jugar, tambien tambien participo en juegos de rol, como dungeons and dragons,y practico softcombat con el grupo estudiantil de la Universidad.</description></item><item><title>Gabriel Ramirez</title><link>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/Members/GabrielRamirez/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/Members/GabrielRamirez/</guid><description>Gabriel Ramirez Leon # Quien Soy # Soy un Estudiante de Ingeniería de Sistemas y Computación de la Universidad Nacional de Colombia. Tengo 24 años y practico artes marciales.
Ilusion visual # La ilusion es un espiral que se crea al trasladar varios cuadrados con el mismo centro de masa y de diferente tamaño.
Código function setup() { createCanvas(500,500); rectMode(CENTER); sliderX=30; sliderY=20; } function draw() { background(150); noFill(); translate(width/2,height/2); for(let x=420; x&amp;gt;= 40; x = x/1.</description></item><item><title>Juan Sierra</title><link>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/Members/JuanSierra/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geramirezl.github.io/visualcomp/docs/Menu/Members/JuanSierra/</guid><description> Juan Guillermo Sierra Agreda # Quien Soy # Ilusion visual #</description></item></channel></rss>